## **(**647) 679-8032

# Alireza Torabian

☑ torabian@yorku.ca

torabian.alireza@gmail.com Graduate Student / Experienced in Machine Learning

% www.eecs.yorku.ca/ torabian/
1997alireza

**in** alireza-torabian

Computer science graduate student at York University researching in the field of machine learning calibration with a strong background in mathematics. Experienced in developing machine learning models and the theory behind them. Have done several projects in various areas, especially deep learning, adversarial machine learning, and NLP, mostly using Tensorflow and Keras.

#### **EDUCATION**

York University 2021-2022 (Expected)

M.Sc. in Computer Science, Advised by Ruth Urner, GPA: A+

Toronto, Canada

Amirkabir University of Technology (Tehran Polytechnic)

2015-2020

B.Sc. in Computer (Software) Engineering, Advised by Saeedeh Momtazi, GPA: 3.9/4 (18.25/20) (In the top 10%)

Tehran, Iran

Thesis: Design and Implementation of a Persian Automatic Question Answering System

#### **EXPERIENCE**

York University Jan. 2021 – Present

Research Assistant, Machine Learning

Toronto, Canada

• Exploring desirable properties of calibration models as well as evaluation metrics and analyze their feasibility and correspondences.

## National University of Singapore, Data Privacy and Trustworthy Machine Learning Research Lab

Jul. 2019 - Sep. 2019

Research Intern, Adversarial Machine Learning

Singapore

- Creating a black-box adversarial attack to fool face recognition models for enhancing face privacy on social media achieved 35% success rate.
- To fool face detection models, the attack model tries to minimize the intersection of the detected face and the original face.
- The face recognition attack model tries to maximize the similarity of the recognized face's latent feature and a target face.

Diaalog

Jul. 2018 – Dec. 2018

Research and Development Intern, NLP

Tehran. Iran

- · Developing a Persian question answering system to generate answers according to the entrance questions in Python Tensorflow.
- Using a sequence-to-sequence model and clustering methods.

### Amirkabir University of Technology, Cognitive Robotics Lab

Oct. 2016 - Sep. 2017

Research Assistant

Tehran, Iran

- Designing an autonomous exploration algorithm for robots to help them explore a map simultaneously and from different starting points in C++.
- A master node merges the scanned maps from all robots and commands them to explore specific points on the map.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages Python, Java, C++, Go

Frameworks and Tools TensorFlow (Python & JS), Keras, Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-learn

Databases MySQL, SPARQL, MongoDB

Web Design JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Express.js, PHP

Other Tools Git, Unix shell, Jupyter

## **PROJECTS**

## Alternative Actor and Co-Star Suggestion Using a Graph Autoencoder Model

Apr. 2021

- Applying a graph autoencoder to a network of actors using Keras in Python achieved 99.46% accuracy on reconstruction the graph.
- An alternative actor is found by searching the latent space using a K-d tree.
- · A co-star is suggested based on the predicted weights in the autoencoder model's target network.

## **Persian Question Answering System**

Aug. 2020

- Generating answers for a question in Persian language based on a knowledge-base in Python.
- SVM and CNN classification models used to classify the question type achieved 96% accuracy and F1-score of 92.7%.

## **Optimization Coursework**

Jul. 2019

- Implementing algorithms to optimize a convex problem.
- Some unconstrained optimizations such as line search and trust region methods, and some constrained optimizations such as log barrier.

## **Neural Dialogue System**

Dec. 2018

• Implementation of a Seq2Seq model with attention mechanism, using **Tensorflow** in **Python**.

## **HONORS AND AWARDS**

| York University Fellowship, C\$62,500 for my master's studies                             | 2021-2022 |
|-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|-----------|
| Second Place in the rescue simulation virtual robot league at RoboCup in Nagoya, Japan    | 2017      |
| Ranked top 0.5% in nationwide Iranian university entrance exam among 180,000 participants | 2015      |
| Member of National Organization for Development of Exceptional Talents (NODET)            | 2011-2015 |